<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>MangoDriod</title>
    <link>https://md.eknath.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on MangoDriod</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.141.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 13:02:29 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://md.eknath.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Your App to Offline First With Room Part 2 (Key Components of Room)</title>
      <link>https://md.eknath.dev/posts/upgrading-your-app-to-offline-first-with-room-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 13:02:29 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://md.eknath.dev/posts/upgrading-your-app-to-offline-first-with-room-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously we discussed about the strategies and picked Google&amp;rsquo;s Room Library,so now lets get started with setting up the library and discuss about the key components of room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;setup&#34;&gt;Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Google has the best article for setting up, I will be skipping the setup up
Dependency setup: &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.android.com/jetpack/androidx/releases/room&#34;&gt;Official Guide on Setting up Room Dependencies and plugins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please do ensure you follow the above guide and then sync and build your project successfully, as it will help you to try out the components yourself. In this article, my intention is to explore the key components of Room, a bare minimum you need to know to implement a simple offline-first app. For a detailed and more complex use case, check out my upcoming article.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upgrading Your App to Offline First With Room Part 1</title>
      <link>https://md.eknath.dev/posts/upgrading-your-app-to-offline-first-with-room-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 09:23:57 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://md.eknath.dev/posts/upgrading-your-app-to-offline-first-with-room-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Making your app Offline first is extremely essential if you intend to provide a better user experience for your users, but not just that it makes your app faster by reduce the number of network call which in turn also reduces the running cost of servers significantly, i can yap more about why this is must but since you have already decided to invest in this lets skip it for now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
